Have you ever noticed if you unplug an
appliance while it's running, like this
hair dryer, then you get a spark? To
make a 1 cm spark in air requires 10,000
V,
but mains voltage is only around 120 to
240 V.
So, where is that extra voltage coming
from? Thanks to Anker for sponsoring
this video. When the hair dryer is on,
current flows through these coils of
wire, but that current also creates a
magnetic field. And so, when you pull
out the plug, you are cutting off that
current suddenly, which means the
magnetic field will rapidly drop to
zero. But, nature hates a sudden change
in magnetic field, so it tries to
compensate. As the magnetic field drops,
it induces a voltage in the coil to try
to maintain that current. And that
voltage can get so high it ionizes the
air between the plug and the socket.
That is the spark that we see. But, this
same effect can actually be quite
useful, because the purpose of a
charger, a wall charger, is to take high
voltage mains electricity and into
smooth low voltage DC for like your
phone or your laptop. And to achieve
that, the current in this device is
switched on and off hundreds of
thousands of times per second using
transistors. [music] That creates all
these little pulses of electricity. Now,
to smooth those out, you require an
inductor, a coil of wire just like in
the hair dryer, just with a very
specific design. Now, this inductor
resists sudden changes in current. It
acts like a shock absorber. So, when the
current rises, it stores energy in a
magnetic field, and then when the
current falls, it releases that energy
again, helping to turn choppy electrical
pulses into steady DC. Now, there is a
trade-off, which is the higher the
voltage the inductor has to handle, the
bigger it needs to be, which is why high
power chargers need really large
inductors. But, Anker has redesigned the
circuitry in their fast chargers using a
technique called MBuck [music] combined
with their custom-built algorithm. So,
instead of doing one large voltage drop
across a single inductor, N-Buck splits
the conversion across multiple levels
and switches it up to 200,000 times per
second. That means the inductor has less
energy to handle for every switch cycle.
So, the inductors can be shrunk to a
quarter of the standard size. That is
what allows Anker to pack 160 watts of
fast charging into a body this compact.
So, check out the link in the
description and pick up your Anker
charger today.